Finding Aid for Commercial catalog collection, 1870s-2000s
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Stoves and Heating Equipment (Box 16)
  - Grand Rapids Welding Supply Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Two brochures advertising Philgas stoves circa 1929 (Box 16)
      (Note: Philgas was a division of the Detroit Stove Co.)
  - Kalamazoo Stove Co., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Again--better savings at factory prices, we pay the freight! Now is the time to buy. circa 1935 (Box 16)
    - Factory prices: heaters, ranges, furnaces, direct from the men who make them. circa 1937 (Box 16)
    - Kalamazoo factory prices: spring sale. circa 1928 (Box 16)
  - L. and L. Jenison Co., Jenison, Mich
    - Large folded broadside advertising Philgas ranges circa 1930 (Folder NB A613 C357)
  - Marshall Furnace Co., Marshall, Mich
    - Marshall all-cast furnace circa 1940 (Box 16)
  - Michigan Stove Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalog circa 1895 (Box 16)
      (Imperfect: missing pages 1-24)
    - Folder circa 1895, 3 leaves (Box 16)
  - Monroe Foundry and Furnace Co., Monroe, Mich
    - The Floral City Furnaces circa 1891 (Box 16)
  - Peninsular Stove Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Peninsular stoves & ranges, Catalog no. 423. circa 1910s (Box 16)
  - Rudy Furnace Co., Dowagiac, Mich
    - Rudy furnaces. circa 1920 (Box 16)
  - Union Heater Supply Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalog of fire pots, gasoline trucks, flat irons, braziers, portable furnaces, etc. circa 1895 (Box 16)
- Seeds--Catalogs and Nurserymen's Products (Box 17)
  - American Seed Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Grass seed and golf course equipment. circa 1920s (Box 17)
  - Anthony, Jon, Lansing, Mich
    - Foliage plants. 1959 (Box 17)
  - Atkins & Durbrow Corporation, Detroit, Mich
    - Peat moss. 1950 (Box 17)
  - Charles M. Baumgarten Seed Co., Bay City, Mich
    - Seed catalog for 1918 [farm, garden, flower seeds] (Box 17)
  - Ensata Gardens, Galesburg, Mich
    - Our 1999, selection of Japanese iris (Box 17)
  - Fraleighs Landscape Nursery, Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Branching out. September 1981 (Box 17)
  - Greening Bros.' Nurseries. Monroe, Monroe, Mich
    - Progressive horticulture in the 20th century. 1901.[some pages damaged] (Box 17)
  - Greening Nursery Co.. Monroe, Monroe, Mich
    - Better homes. circa 1920s (Box 17)
    - Born 1850, still growing. circa 1938 (Box 17)
    - Catalogue of the Greening Nursery Co. circa 1905 (Box 17)
      [some pages damaged]
    - Greening's book of horticulture. 1922 (Box 17)
    - Plant Ameri 1950s (Box 17)
  - Hammond, Harry N. Fifield, [Sagninaw Co.], Mich
    - Annual catalog of vegetable and flower seeds circa 1900 (Box 17)
  - Hill Top Orchards & Nurseries, inc., Hartford, Mich
    - Special price list for orchardists. Fall 1963-Spring 1964, circa 1962 (Box 17)
  - Hill, George W., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue and price list of garden seeds circa 1892 (Box 17)
  - Hinkle, C. R., Saint Joseph, Mich
    - Gladioli of quality. 1924 (Box 17)
  - Monroe Nursery Co., Monroe, Mich
    - Price list. No. 120. Fall 1921, Spring 1922 (Box 17)
    - Price list. No. 126. Fall 1926-Spring 1927 (Box 17)
    - Wholesale price list. No. 958A. circa 1954 (Box 17)
  - Newhall Nursery, Grandville, Mich
    - The ten commandments of phlox culture. 1934 (Box 17)
  - Pontiac Nursery Co., Romeo, Mich
    - Pontiac Nurseries. circa 1938 (Box 17)
    - Pontiac planting guide. circa 1920s (Box 17)
    - Your home grounds can be beautiful! circa 1947 (Box 17)
    - [Price list] circa 1942 (Folder NB A613 C357)
  - Sutton, T. I., Lenawee Co., Mich
    - Descriptive circular ... seed wheat Fall 1886 (Box 17)
  - Westcroft Gardens, Grosse Ile, Mich
    - Greenleaf compound no. 1 Undated (Folder NB A613 C357)
    - Herbaceous, perennial and rock plants, choice landscape materials, climbing vines, garden supplies. circa 1930s (Box 17)
    - Korea, land of enchantment. undated (Box 17)
    - Westcroft Gardens. circa 1930s (Box 17)
  - Whitten-Ackerman Nurseries, Bridgman, Mich
    - Complete line of nursery stock direct to grower. 1929 (Box 17)
  - Windsor Nurseries, Windsor, Ont
    - Catalogue of fruit and ornamental trees, shrubs, flowers, etc... to be sold at auction September 30, 1862 [printed in Detroit] (Box 17)
- Tombstones (Box 18)
  - Johnson & Sherman, Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Verses and epitaphs for gravestones tombs and monuments circa 1867 (Box 18)
- Toys
  - Aristoplay, Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Catalog. 1997 (Box 18)
  - Fulton Manufacturing Co., Bay City, Mich
    - Catalog of toys [go-carts, baby carriages, pullman sleepers, reed carriages, sulkies and service wagons] 1916 (Box 18)
  - Kalamazoo Toy Train Works, Bangor, Mich
    - Kalamazoo toy trains. (Box 18)
  - Lloyd Manufacturing Co., Menominee, Mich
    - Lloyd loom products: baby carriages, doll buggies, furniture. Catalog 101 1923, (Wicker products) (Volume 5)
  - Pratt Manufacturing Co., Coldwater, Mich
    - Sleds. (Box 18)
- Washing Machines
  - Brewster, E. E., Holly, Mich
    - Broadside advertising laundry soap and sewing needles circa 1887 (Folder NB A613 C357)
  - Florin Manufacturing Co., Carson City, Mich
    - Leaflet advertising the Florin washing machine circa 1905 (Box 18)
- Weaving--Patterns
  - Cromaine Crafts, Hartland, Mich
    - The shuttle service. (Box 18)
- Wrought Iron
  - Barnes Wire Fence Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Barnes wire & iron products. Bulletin no. 22 (Box 18)
  - E. T. Barnum Iron and Wire Works, Detroit, Mich
    - General catalogue, no. 570. [fences, window guards, vault doors, fire escapes, stairs, jail cells, etc.] 1920 (Box 18)
  - Jackson Fence Co., Jackson, Mich
    - Jackson stiff stay fence. undated (Box 18)
  - Michigan Wire and Iron Works, Detroit, Mich
    - Special Iron fence supplement. No. 3 March, 1891 (Box 18)
      [includes vault gates, jail cells and cages, bedsteads]
  - Page Woven Wire Fence Co., Adrian, Mich
    - Page fences. Catalog no. 22 1926 (Box 18)
    - Wrought iron fences. Catalog no. 53 1917 (Box 18)